Lukas Cunningham

SUMMARY

Driven software developer with outstanding problem-solving, analytical, and interpersonal skills. Seeking to leverage 5 years of professional experience across various industries into the fast-paced environment of a forward-looking company.

Languages: Java, Python, C++, JavaScript, SQL, PHP, Linux

EDUCATION

Colorado School of Mines, Golden, CO

May 2024

Master of Science in Computer Science

GPA: 4.0

GPA: 3.9

Awards and Involvement: Association for Computing Machinery, Treasurer of Chess Club, Mountain Biking Club

Relevant Coursework: Algorithms and Data Structures, Machine Learning, Operating Systems, Architecture, Cyber Security

Foothill College, Los Altos Hills, CA

June 2021 - July 2022

Department of Computer Science **Awards and Involvement**: Dean's List, Vice President of AI and Data Science Club

Relevant Coursework: Algorithms, Data Structures, Object-Oriented Programming, Software Engineering, Data Science

Southern Methodist University, Dallas, TX

August 2014 - December 2018

Bachelor of Business Administration in Finance, Minor in Mathematics

Awards and Involvement: Dean's List, Cornerstone Scholarship, Discovery Scholarship, Hilltop Scholars, Finance Club

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

Chess

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HP Inc, San Diego, CA: Software Developer Intern

May 2023 - Present

- 1
- 2
- 3
- 4

Datava, Wheat Ridge, CO: Software Engineer

October 2022 – May 2023

- Designed and integrated web applications into existing customer relationship management software
- · Worked with an interdisciplinary development team to implement new features and fix defects
- Decomposed epics into features and user stories for our scrum team

A Place in the Sun, Phoenix, AZ: Portfolio Manager

April 2020 – July 2022

- Marketed, supervised, and managed the financing of a 16 single-family property portfolio in Phoenix
- Performed comparative analyses and orchestrated refinances to maximize rent revenue and optimize capital allocation
- Implemented software to streamline applications, rental payments, prospective tenant screenings, and maintenance

U.S. Peace Corps, Guinea, Africa: Mathematics Education Volunteer

July 2019 - March 2020

- Lesson planned and taught mathematics and English to over 200 high school students in French
- Led an economic initiative alongside local government officials and business owners to repurpose plastic into goods
- Formed and led a girls' soccer team, worked alongside community officials for field access and equipment
- Founding member of the Peace Corps Guinea Sustainability Sub-Committee

Specialty Tutors, Dallas, TX: Tutor/Mentor

October 2016 - December 2018

- Mentored K-12 students with learning disadvantages and devised long-term strategies to improve their study habits
- Integrated parents into the process of improving their student's study and organization skills

SKILLS

- Professional: Debugging, Scrum, Project Management, Communication, Sales, Consulting, Community Engagement
- Foreign Languages: French: Certified Intermediate High LPI, Spanish: Limited Proficiency